

# Ph.D. Student at Georgia Tech

# RESEARCH INTERESTS \_\_\_\_

#### NATURAL LANGUAGE PROCESSING (NLP)

LARGE LANGUAGE MODELS, RETRIEVAL-BASED NLP, EFFICIENCY, ROBUSTNESS

The long-term goal of my research is to enhance the *practicality* of NLP systems (e.g., Large Language Models) so that they can be widely used in real-world scenarios. In particular, my research focuses on i) how to make NLP models cheaper (i.e., efficient) in terms of data, parameters, or compute, and ii) how to build NLP models that are robust to unseen cases in the wild.

# EDUCATION

#### GEORGIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

Atlanta, GA, USA

Ph.D. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Aug. 2022 - Present

- Research Assistant at NLP Lab (Advisors: Dr. Alan Ritter, Dr. Wei Xu)
- GPA: 4.0 / 4.0

### KOREA ADVANCED INSTITUTE OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY (KAIST)

Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Feb. 2019 - Feb. 2021

M.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

• Research Assistant at IR&NLP Lab (Advisor: Dr. Sung-Hyon Myaeng)

- Thesis committee: Dr. Sung-Hyong Myaeng, Dr. Hojin Choi, Dr. Alice Oh
- GPA: 4.03 / 4.30

B.E. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE & ENGINEERING

Daejeon, Republic of Korea Mar. 2012 - Feb. 2019

Summa Cum Laude

CHUNGNAM NATIONAL UNIVERSITY

GPA: 4.30 / 4.50 (Rank: 1/125 in CSE, Major GPA: 4.41)

# PUBLICATIONS

- \* indicates equal contribution
- [1] Discern and Answer: Mitigating the Impact of Misinformation in Retrieval-Augmented Models with Discriminators Preprint

Giwon Hong\*, Jeonghwan Kim\*, Junmo Kang\*, Sung-Hyon Myaeng, Joyce Jiyoung Whang [pdf]

[2] Distill or Annotate? Cost-Efficient Fine-Tuning of Compact Models Junmo Kang, Wei Xu, Alan Ritter [pdf]

ACL 2023

[3] Graph-Induced Transformers for Efficient Multi-Hop Question Answering Giwon Hong, Jeonghwan Kim, Junmo Kang, Sung-Hyon Myaeng [pdf]

**EMNLP 2022** 

[4] Exploiting Numerical-Contextual Knowledge to Improve Numerical Reasoning in Question Answering Findings of NAACL 2022

Jeonghwan Kim, Junmo Kang, Giwon Hong, Kyung-min Kim, Sung-Hyon Myaeng [pdf]

[5] Ultra-High Dimensional Sparse Representations with Binarization for Efficient Text Retrieval EMNLP 2021

Kyoung-Rok Jang, Junmo Kang, Giwon Hong, Sung-Hyon Myaeng, Joohee Park, Taewon Yoon, Heecheol Seo [pdf]

[6] Leveraging Order-Free Tag Relations for Context-Aware Recommendation Junmo Kang, Jeonghwan Kim, Suwon Shin, Sung-Hyon Myaeng [pdf]

**EMNLP 2021** 

- [7] Have You Seen That Number? Investigating Extrapolation in Question Answering Models EMNLP 2021 Jeonghwan Kim, Giwon Hong, Kyung-min Kim, Junmo Kang, Sung-Hyon Myaeng [pdf]
- [8] Can You Distinguish Truthful from Fake Reviews? User Analysis and Assistance Tool for Fake Review Detection HCI+NLP@EACL 2021
  Jeonghwan Kim\*, Junmo Kang\*, Suwon Shin\*, Sung-Hyon Myaeng [pdf]
- [9] Regularization of Distinct Strategies for Unsupervised Question Generation

  Junmo Kang\*, Giwon Hong\*, Haritz Puerto San Roman\*, Sung-Hyon Myaeng [pdf]
- [10] Handling Anomalies of Synthetic Questions in Unsupervised Question Answering
  Giwon Hong\*, Junmo Kang\*, Doyeon Lim\*, Sung-Hyon Myaeng [pdf]
- [11] Let Me Know What to Ask: Interrogative-Word-Aware Question Generation

  Junmo Kang\*, Haritz Puerto San Roman\*, Sung-Hyon Myaeng [pdf]

MRQA@EMNLP 2019

# EXPERIENCES

MIT-IBM WATSON AI LAB

Cambridge, MA, USA

RESEARCH INTERN

May. 2023 - Aug. 2023 (Expected)

· Working on large language models.

GEORGIA TECH NLP LAB

Atlanta, GA, USA

**GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT** 

Aug. 2022 - Present

· Worked on cost-efficiency analysis of small and large language models [2].

KAIST IR&NLP LAB Daejeon, Republic of Korea

RESEARCH ASSOCIATE Mar. 2021 - Jul. 2022

- Worked on robust retrieval-augmented LMs [1].
- Worked on efficient methods for multi-hop QA [3].

KAIST IR&NLP LAB Daejeon, Republic of Korea

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Feb. 2019 - Feb. 2021

- Worked on question generation and unsupervised question answering for data-efficiency [9,10,11].
- Presented sample-efficient and robust number representations for question answering [7,4].
- Proposed a novel generation model that takes into account the inter-dependency of tags while alleviating the order sensitivity [6].
- Proposed a novel sparse representation model for passage retrieval that can take advantage of an efficient inverted index and symbolic IR techniques [5].

REPUBLIC OF KOREA ARMY Republic of Korea

HONORABLY DISCHARGED AS SERGEANT

Apr. 2013 - Jan. 2015

Compulsory military service.

May 2, 2023 Junmo Kang - CV 2 / 3

# HONORS & AWARDS \_\_\_\_\_

Graduated with Highest Honor in CSE, Chungnam National University	2019
Grand Prize, Business ICT Competition	2018
Excellence Award, Startup Competition	2018
Finalist, NAVER AI Hackathon	2018
Grand Prize, Daejeon Startup School	2017
Best Excellence Award, Startup Picnic	2016
Finalist, Microsoft Imagine Cup Korea	2016